A Guide to the Office of the President, Special Records, ca. 1967-1979
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Office of the President, Special Records ca. 1967-1979
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-2/1/3.801
This collection consists of 1,800 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access is prohibited for ten years from the date of creation unless special permission is granted by the President's Office. Under the terms of the Virginia Freedom of Information Act (Sec. 2.1-343 (4)), the records of the President or other chief executive officer of any state-supported institution of higher education are exempt from the law's access provisions. Access restrictions may apply to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Acquisition Information
This collection is an archival transfer to the library by the Office of the President, Pavilion VIII University of Virginia on 1981 February 23.
Scope and Content Information
Special record files of the Office of the President including material regarding The Bicentennial, The Lawn Society, and The Medical School.
Contents List
- Ad Hoc Committee Files
  - Dean of School of Commerce, Search for 1976-1977 (Box 1)
  - Director of University Police, Search for 1977 (Box 1)
  - Lambeth Field Housing 1970-1976 (Box 1)
  - Post Office/Mail Delivery 1974-1975 (Box 1)
  - Vice President for Development, Search for 1976 (Box 1)
- Special Committee Files
  - Administration Building 1970-1977 (Box 1)
  - Cemetery 1967-1974 (Box 1)
  - Health Science Library Bridge 1974 June (Box 1)
  - Landscape, North Grounds 1971-1979 (Box 1)
  - Law/Graduate School of Business Administration [Darden] Complex (Copley) 1970-1976 (Box 1)
  - Law/Graduate School of Business Administration [Darden] Dining Facility 1974-1976 (Box 1)
  - Medical Isotopes 1970-1975 (Box 1)
  - Radioactive Waste Management Facility 1974-1978 (Box 2)
  - Science Library 1974 (Box 2)
  - Survey and Maintenance (Formal Gardens) 1973-1976 (Box 2)
  - Telecommunications 1974-1976 (Box 2)
  - University Airport 1968-1975 (Box 2)
  - University Becoming Part of Charlottesville 1972-1973 (Box 2)
  - Urology and Orthopedice 1975-1978 (Box 2)
- General Files
  - Administrative Committee 1974-1979 (Box 3)
  - Bicentennial Commission (Charlottesville/Albemarle) 1970-1974 (Box 3)
  - Bicentennial Committee - Minutes 1974-1976 (Box 3)
  - Bicentennial, in Cooperation with Universities of Massachusetts and Pennsylvania 1974 (Box 3)
  - Bicentennial Planning Committee (University of Virginia) 1970-1977, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Lawn Society 1977 (Box 4)
  - Looney, W.B.-Medical Center Personnel 1975-1977 (Box 4)
  - United Way 1974-1978, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Virginia Independence Bicentennial Commission 1970-1977 (Box 4)